Let's explore functions, starting with y equals 2x. Watch as we plot this
line and see how each input x gives us an output y that's
twice its value. For example, when x is 1, y becomes 2.
Let's explore a single artificial neuron - the building block
of neural networks. As we draw it, notice how inputs
flow through weighted connections into the neuron body, which then
processes and outputs a signal using an activation function.
Here's our neural network with three layers. Input nodes
in blue receive data, which flows through green hidden
nodes, and finally reaches red output nodes - creating
a complete pathway for information processing.
Let's see how a simple neural network learns. Starting with two
weights connecting three nodes, we'll process an input of 2 to
predict an output. After seeing the error, the network adjusts its
weights to get closer to the desired result of 1.
Here's a written digit 7, passed through a neural network.
As the pixels flow into input nodes, they connect through
a hidden layer, leading to ten possible digit outputs. The
network confidently identifies this as the number 7.